<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Isaac Samuel</title>
    <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Isaac Samuel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 19:04:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>True Love&#39;s Kiss</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/true-loves-kiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/true-loves-kiss/</guid>
      <description>There is a cruelty to the fairy godmothers, though they don&amp;rsquo;t mean it that way; there is an inhumanity to their love of lessons and surprise twists. If a man falls ill of a deadly sickness, his fairy godmother cannot simply alleviate his suffering and send him on his way.
Oh, she has the power to just heal him, to be certain. She has the power to transform mice into horses, if she pleases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Divorce Settlement of the Magi</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/divorce/</guid>
      <description>Hot off the presses of my diseased mind:
The Divorce Settlement of the Magi
A deeply embittered, deeply unpleasant couple approach a divorce lawyer. The husband hates his wife for hoarding; rooms of their house are filled with her scrap-booking material and he&amp;rsquo;s drowning in it. The wife hates her husband for abandoning her; he spends all his time in the garage, drinking beer and working on cars.
The couple is childless and they can&amp;rsquo;t afford to get a court involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A WHOLE NEW (CONSEQUENTIALIST) WORLD</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/aladdin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/aladdin/</guid>
      <description>In honor of the new Aladdin movie I watched here in Pune, I present a brief fanfiction of a counterfactual universe where at least SOMEONE has a concept of moral responsibility.
A WHOLE NEW (CONSEQUENTIALIST) WORLD
Aladdin&amp;rsquo;s face was grim but at peace, as for the final time the prince-turned-street-rat sought to command the blue being of phenomenal cosmic power. He was prepared, after everything, to leave behind the wealth, power, and hope he had just so briefly gotten a taste of.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
