<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Namaskar, yaar. on Isaac Samuel</title>
    <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Namaskar, yaar. on Isaac Samuel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 19:04:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eye Heart Eyes</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/eyes/</guid>
      <description>Wearing masks have really focused my attention on the diversity, expressiveness, and beauty of eyes. I kind of get why artists and poets are so obsessed with them.
(However, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from experience that it&amp;rsquo;s typically an oddball thing to compliment strangers on. 😂 I&amp;rsquo;m typically really free about saying &amp;ldquo;I love your hair!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Nice tattoo, man!&amp;rdquo; to random people. But complimenting people&amp;rsquo;s eyes usually comes across as flirting, or as being on drugs or something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Field is not the Job</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/day-to-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/day-to-day/</guid>
      <description>One thing I see people do a lot when choosing a career - not just teenagers, but adults - is conflating a field or a job title with the actual day-to-day of a job.
As an example, my best friend in high school wanted to be a wildlife researcher for most of her life. She had presumably visualized tracking wolves in some remote forest, observing their behaviour, and being in the woods for months at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Ethos</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ethos/</guid>
      <description>Word vomit on building an &amp;ldquo;ethos&amp;rdquo;/ code of ethics, for the masochistic. (Fair warning: it&amp;rsquo;s very &amp;ldquo;written to a friend at 3AM&amp;rdquo;. Have mercy.) So I always kind of hate how in discussions about fictional characters, or even in-universe, when people judge characters based on what they did in moments of extreme stress. But it&amp;rsquo;s actually a pretty common way of seeing the world. Obviously many believe in things like critical moments where we really get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On &#39;two-hour&#39; friendships</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/two-hour-friendships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/two-hour-friendships/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, I took a trip to NYC. Before the trip, I killed time by pacing outside the greyhound station. I don&amp;rsquo;t smoke, but when a desi guy came outside and started puffing away, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to bum a cigarette and show off my hindi.
By coincidence, we ended up sitting in adjacent rows of seats on the bus ride, and then happily sat together when the bus got overcrowded and some had to eschew social distancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horrible History</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ancesteral-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ancesteral-trauma/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when reading about history, my jaw drops at just how just how cruel the world was. In 1398, just outside of Delhi, the conqueror Amir Taimur killed around 100,000 people. Why? He had captured them, and was worried that they might revolt. This could turn the tides of the next battle, perhaps the war.
So, very logically, he ordered that they all 100,000 people&amp;ndash;lives, families, dreams, and pets&amp;ndash;be slaughtered. (If you, like me, struggle at first glance to emotionally feel anything when you read this, try imagining specific loved ones being killed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formalising Classification Schema</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/classification-schema/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/classification-schema/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m temporarily staying near a state park and have had a lot of opportunity to do my favourite thing&amp;ndash;extended walks in nature where I can go down deep holes I’d typically consider best left to rabbits with pocket watches. Today, my brain apparently decided it was time to formalise and classify different types of nuance (because nothing is more nuanced than a formal classification schema).
I think that one of the most important skills for thinking fairly and accurately is considering nuance: resisting binary dichotomies on complex and important topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindi troubles</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/spanish/</guid>
      <description>Accidentally asked my hispanic neighbors &amp;ldquo;Spanish samajatha hain?&amp;rdquo; 🤦‍♂️ Apparently for my subconcious, there are two languages: English and Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On rights</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/rights/</guid>
      <description>In a perfectly totalitarian society, everything that is not approved is criminal. In a perfectly free society, nothing is criminal. In every society that actually exists, there&amp;rsquo;s a middle ground: there are many things we allow people to do even if we don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re a good idea.
For example, in most western countries, it&amp;rsquo;s perfectly legal to eat yourself to morbid obesity, get blackout drunk every night, make flat-earth videos on YouTube, deny the Holocaust, or swear at your boss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Superpowers</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/superpowers/</guid>
      <description>(Just repaired my old laptop, and I&amp;rsquo;m going through my diary entries. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad they were recoverable. Here&amp;rsquo;s one of my (somewhat emotional) retrospectives that I had started a few months ago and finished just now.)
There was some thread online talking about &amp;ldquo;travel superpowers&amp;rdquo;, such as the ability to fall asleep easily in transit, to negotiate with pedlars, or to find cheap accommodation. My answer is something I inherited from my dad - a blithe fearlessness for my physical safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone-y Bologna</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/time/</guid>
      <description>Me: &amp;ldquo;Where does all my time go? How am I supposed to get anything done? When&amp;rsquo;s the last time I even ate?&amp;rdquo;
Also Me: Spends an hour on the phone with his friend in India
Spends fourty-five minutes on the phone with his friend living three blocks away
Spends an hour and a half on the phone with his best friend&amp;rsquo;s mom
Spends an hour and a half on the phone with his former boss</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boxer Shorts</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/boxers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/boxers/</guid>
      <description>Very random fun fact&amp;ndash;in India, it is customary for men to wear a second pair of underwear underneath their boxers. Which turns them into acceptable loungewear and marginally acceptable attire for a very casual motorcycle ride down to the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding is wizardy</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/tech/wizardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/tech/wizardy/</guid>
      <description>I spent my childhood eternally frustrated by Harry Potter and Ron Weasley for their extreme lack of curiosity for the magical world. Dropped into the world&amp;rsquo;s premier magic prep school, their reaction was &amp;ldquo;mehhhhh, let&amp;rsquo;s cut class and play Quidditch.&amp;rdquo; Quidditch is awesome&amp;ndash;flying in general is awesome&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m sure Hermione is missing out. But at least she is expressing what seems like the only sane reaction to discovering magic is real&amp;ndash;sheer wonder and excitement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/github/</guid>
      <description>Me: Oh, this really long elaborate GitHub issue I wrote two years ago is overcomplicating this. I can do a much simpler thing! Let me just do that.
Me: (spends time doing simple thing)
Me: WAIT AHHHHH
Me: NO THIS DOES NOT WORK WHY DID I NOT TRUST 2016 ME WHO OBVIOUSLY THOUGHT THIS THROUGH DAMN IT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Love&#39;s Kiss</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/true-loves-kiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/true-loves-kiss/</guid>
      <description>There is a cruelty to the fairy godmothers, though they don&amp;rsquo;t mean it that way; there is an inhumanity to their love of lessons and surprise twists. If a man falls ill of a deadly sickness, his fairy godmother cannot simply alleviate his suffering and send him on his way.
Oh, she has the power to just heal him, to be certain. She has the power to transform mice into horses, if she pleases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True Love&#39;s Kiss</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/divorce/</guid>
      <description>Hot off the presses of my diseased mind:
THE DIVORCE SETTLEMENT OF THE MAGI
A deeply embittered, deeply unpleasant couple approach a divorce lawyer. The husband hates his wife for hoarding; rooms of their house are filled with her scrap-booking material and he&amp;rsquo;s drowning in it. The wife hates her husband for abandoning her; he spends all his time in the garage, drinking beer and working on cars.
The couple is childless and they can&amp;rsquo;t afford to get a court involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gora Problems</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/foriegners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/foriegners/</guid>
      <description>Had an exceptionally good day in Indore, topped by a conversation with a stand-up comedian named Div, who was curious about my perception of India. (I asked him if he had more than fifteen minutes for me to adequately respond to that, and he pointed out that, if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, we were both sitting alone on a Friday night eating &amp;ldquo;fucking poha&amp;rdquo;.) At some point, I mentioned that on the way there, the auto driver had stopped and introduced me to two of his friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maratha Blues</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/smelly-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/smelly-breath/</guid>
      <description>#1 on the list of things I don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate about Maharastra: How I kind of like the taste of raw onions after living here. This is NOT good for your love lives, guys, just remember that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isaac&#39;s Checklist For Hard-Balling Autowallas...</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/autowalla/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/autowalla/</guid>
      <description>Isaac&amp;rsquo;s Checklist For Hard-Balling Autowallas That Start Out The Negotiation At 3.5x The Amount You Know It Actually Should Cost To Get To Your Destination:
1.) An amused smile and a &amp;ldquo;Baaaaaaaaapre.&amp;rdquo; The longer and more drawn out, the better&amp;ndash;this is a sign of virility in the Maratha culture. Men often sit in a circle and contest each other with how long they can draw out their &amp;ldquo;bapre&amp;quot;s. Having asserted your masculinity, offer the fair price times 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do-uble Entendre</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/maruti-esteem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/maruti-esteem/</guid>
      <description>I was on an online forum discussing some of India&amp;rsquo;s greatest unsolved mysteries, and someone wrote &amp;ldquo;One of the unsolved mysteries is that someone stole my self esteem and I can&amp;rsquo;t get it back.&amp;rdquo; Until I read someone&amp;rsquo;s response (&amp;ldquo;Bhai Tinder uninstall kar do, self respect wapas aa jayegi&amp;rdquo;), I somehow parsed the poster as saying that his car (a Maruti Esteem) had been stolen.
I should have been tipped off by the idea that someone had stolen that model of car, if nothing else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reunion</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/hugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/hugs/</guid>
      <description>Meeting my best friend Sashank for the first time in a year, and pretty darn ecstatic about it.
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from me.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from Jayesh.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from Meg.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from Meg&amp;rsquo;s mom.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;And my gram gives you the option of either a hug or her love, because she remembers from what I&amp;rsquo;ve described that you&amp;rsquo;re not prone to physical displays of affection and doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to quote &amp;lsquo;freak you out&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A WHOLE NEW (CONSEQUENTIALIST) WORLD</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/aladdin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/fiction/aladdin/</guid>
      <description>In honor of the new Aladdin movie I watched here in Pune, I present a brief fanfiction of a counterfactual universe where at least SOMEONE has a concept of moral responsibility.
A WHOLE NEW (CONSEQUENTIALIST) WORLD
Aladdin&amp;rsquo;s face was grim but at peace, as for the final time the prince-turned-street-rat sought to command the blue being of phenomenal cosmic power. He was prepared, after everything, to leave behind the wealth, power, and hope he had just so briefly gotten a taste of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bajaranji Bakvaas</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bajarangi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bajarangi/</guid>
      <description>The eighth Harry Potter movie is showing on TV. Harry and Ron are frantically changing out of wet clothes after jumping into a lake
$Host_Sister: &amp;ldquo;Why don&amp;rsquo;t they just change their clothes using magic?&amp;rdquo;
Isaac (aggrieved): &amp;ldquo;If Hanuman could grow so big he could fly a mountain from the Himalayas, why didn&amp;rsquo;t he just carry the army into Lanka instead of making everyone build a land bridge?&amp;rdquo;
Cue: Twenty-minute family argument, /w some yelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Exchange</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bribing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bribing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Arre, you bribed the ticket walla?!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;No I didn&amp;rsquo;t! I tipped him&amp;hellip; and he gave me super special service in return. I mean, nobody was using these seats [in first class] and apparently they have the discretion to upgrade people.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;And you just paid him to use his discretion. That is called bribing.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Well, in America we call it tipping.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysterious Ways</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/brains-mysterious-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/brains-mysterious-ways/</guid>
      <description>Brains work in, uh, mysterious ways. Today, I observed the weirdest instance of mine getting its &amp;ldquo;wires crossed&amp;rdquo;.
In lieu of change, a salesclerk gave me a couple pieces of expresso candy. My intention afterwards was to eat a piece of candy and simultaneously start a work task.
I sat down and popped the candy in my mouth, all according to plan. But suddenly, I felt a surge of alarm, convinced for a split-second that I had somehow eaten the task I was intending to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karthick Bhee Hain</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/dostana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/dostana/</guid>
      <description>Adventures working as a server in an Indian restaurant
Isaac (to customer): &amp;ldquo;Aapka naam kyaa hain [to call when your order is ready]?&amp;rdquo;
Customer: &amp;ldquo;Karthick hoon.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Oh, is it? Ek second, meh phone call lena zarurat hoon.&amp;rdquo; Mimes picking up the phone &amp;ldquo;Wow, call aap ke lie!&amp;rdquo;
Customer: &amp;ldquo;Kyaa?&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Voh bol ki uska naam Karthick bhee hain. I guess&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s Karthick calling Karthick.&amp;rdquo;
Customer &amp;amp; friend: look confused and then laugh simutanously</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meh Americano Samajatha Hoon</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/coffee-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/coffee-india/</guid>
      <description>Am at the airport in Bangalore. On less than an hour sleep, I did what had to be the most stereotypically American-tourist thing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done (and I feel no shame).
Worker: &amp;ldquo;Sir, what kind [of coffee] would you like?&amp;rdquo;
Me: &amp;ldquo;Uhhhh, what are the options?&amp;rdquo;
Worker: &amp;ldquo;Sir, cappachino, americano, latte&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Do you have just like, regular coffee?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pani Hai</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/rum-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/rum-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>On my daily commute home, I was carrying some rum to share for a birthday party in our P.G. After my bag went through the scanner at the metro station and I retrieved it, the female guard ran after me and indicated I needed to talk to the analyst about something he saw on the scanner.
Analyst: &amp;ldquo;Water bottle?&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Nei nei. Um&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Unzips bag to show contents)
Analyst (smiling as he examines the rum bottle): &amp;ldquo;Water bottle hai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwraveling the Indian Head Bobble</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/head-bobble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/head-bobble/</guid>
      <description>After much time and study, I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve finally cracked the mystery of the Indian Head-Bobble.
All people with association to Indian culture will surely know about the Indian head-bobble. More common in the south than the north, it&amp;rsquo;s a curious side-to-side motion, something like tilting your head around the x-axis.
When I came to India the first time, I first thought it was a somehow deferential way of saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m neither confirming nor denying your assumption&amp;rdquo;, because I saw a teenager use it instead of actually answering when questioned about his activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Service</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/customer-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/customer-service/</guid>
      <description>One of the many idiosyncrasies of India is its customer service.
On one hand, you have the infamous call centers that require 35 digit confirmation numbers (or God help you) and that can&amp;rsquo;t ever seem to use common sense if it requires going off-script. Banks where you literally have to negotiate to open a checking account, or who will send you to three different branches to avoid dealing with you. Thoroughly spiteful building managers who turn off the elevator when guests are over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Relations in the Bangalore P.G.: The Screenplay</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cultural-relations-pg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cultural-relations-pg/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved into a P.G. (personal guest) here in Bangalore, a low-commitment and (in this case) dirt-cheap accommodation that provides food twice daily, perfect for migrant workers and students.
My room is literally a bed in a hallway, so I spend a lot of time interacting with the people who live with me - playing cards, discussing politics, and drinking mystery liqour with a suspicious origin.
Thus, I present a 100% accurate screenplay:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gunner</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cs-chest-beating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cs-chest-beating/</guid>
      <description>Today we got back our midterms in my computer science-oriented Probability and Statistics course. The TA told us the highest score was a 48 (out of fifty) and the lowest was in the tens but the average was somewhere in the thirties. The grade will be curved.
Computer science is a discipline full of chest-beating, maybe due to being skewed male and rife with impostor syndrome. One guy in particular is a good example - he complained loudly about covering the material in India during his tenth grade year, he has a tendency to blurt out the answer pre-emptively when the professor is guiding the class on a problem, and he frequently laughs when other students ask a question he feels is obvious (and takes it on himself to explain the answer as condescendingly as humanly possible).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Five Minute Deconstruction of Free Will</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/free-will/</guid>
      <description>(This way-too-long, way-too-digressive response was written for a discussion about the nature of poverty and whether or not it&amp;rsquo;s a choice. There&amp;rsquo;s a much easier argument to be made that poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t much of a choice in most cases without delving into the philosophical topic of free will, but I&amp;rsquo;m doing this for free, so this is what you get.)
There are a number of approaches you can take to dissolve the concept of free will, and/or the concept of personal responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux Maturity</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/faux-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/faux-maturity/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms of faux maturity:
 Avoiding things you&amp;rsquo;d find fun because they are not what an &amp;ldquo;adult&amp;rdquo; does. (E.g. Dyeing your hair purple, playing video games.) Doing things you hate because they ARE what an &amp;ldquo;adult&amp;rdquo; does. (Buying a house, tending to a lawn, smoking, drinking coffee or alcohol.) Shaming or thinking less of people for doing harmless but weird or non-age-typical things. (Scoffing at someone for watching cartoons or putting M&amp;amp;Ms on their pizza.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Bias in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/tech/algorithmic-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/tech/algorithmic-bias/</guid>
      <description>A few days back I read this article about algorithmic bias. Its argument as far as I can tell is as follows: When people complain about algorithms being biased (e.g. racially), they aren&amp;rsquo;t understanding how algorithms work. The algorithms are just performing statistics. The same statistics that reliably decide whether an email is spam or not spam, the same statistics that biologists use to study populations. Race factually correlates with things like the probability of a criminal reoffending, and all the algorithms are doing is correctly calculating the probability that a given criminal is going to reoffend based on the available data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropological Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/crosscultural-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/crosscultural-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>Isaac&amp;rsquo;s mandatory mental checklist whilst hanging out with his (majority desi / south asian) friends:
 Make an extremely convoluted conclusion about desi culture. What observations cause you to draw this conclusion? What assumptions are supporting the way you notice and interpret those actions? In what scenarios could those assumptions possibly be legitimate or illegitimate, and is that even a clearly defined boundary? Am I overthinking this? I’m overthinking this. This is not how a normal person hangs out with their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s called shoestring travelling, and there&#39;s a SUBREDDIT, thank you</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/where-are-your-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/where-are-your-parents/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s completely possible to travel in India for less than $200 a month. You just have to be willing to give up all pretense of safety and comfort. Mostly, just be gregarious with people you meet in general and even on the street - they&amp;rsquo;ll invite you to stay with them, and your travels will totally be enriched.&amp;rdquo;
Boss (exasperated, horrified): &amp;ldquo;Isaac, where were your parents?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakari Bakvaas</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/goats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/goats/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s just replace every word in every sentence with the word &amp;lsquo;goat&amp;rsquo;. Ready? Goat.&amp;rdquo;
$FRIEND_1: &amp;ldquo;Goat goat goat goat.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Goat goat goat. Goat goat goat goat goat goat?&amp;rdquo;
$FRIEND_1: &amp;ldquo;Goat. Goat?&amp;rdquo;
$FRIEND_2: &amp;ldquo;Haha, alright guys.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Goat goat?! Goat goat, goat goat goat goat goat goat! GOAT!&amp;rdquo; shakes Sashank &amp;ldquo;GOOOOAAAAAT!&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramayario</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/ramario/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/ramario/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely the last thing on my priority list right now, but it occurred to me that it would be a lot of fun to make a Ramayana version of the Mario games where Mario is Rama, Sita is Peach, Donkey Kong is Hanuman, and Bowser is Ravana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSI: Applied Statistics</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/csi-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/csi-data-science/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a notion in my mind for a long time&amp;ndash;that the &amp;lsquo;unsexy&amp;rsquo; engineering jobs save more lives than firefighters and first-responders do, by building buildings, cars, and systems (including the equipment firefighters use) to be safe and functional. (So if you want to do something good for the world with you career, being a firefighter works, but keep in mind that people don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate the hard-working engineers whenever a bridge doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall down or when their cell works to call 911 in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monkey Business</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/monkey-buisiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/monkey-buisiness/</guid>
      <description>(While hiking in a state park with a friend recently from Mumbai)
Friend: &amp;ldquo;Isaac, you should ask one of us to watch of your bag while you&amp;rsquo;re climbing.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;I feel pretty safe. Are you worried about something in particular?&amp;rdquo;
Friend: &amp;ldquo;Monkeys could get into it and mess with your stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that happen so many times.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Monkeys are less of a problem in the US.&amp;rdquo;
Friend (skeptically): &amp;ldquo;Okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Nuance in Racial Discourse</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/thinking-with-naunce-in-race-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/thinking-with-naunce-in-race-discussion/</guid>
      <description>Thought experiment time!
Gina is an upper-middle-class woman who works as a professor in a university in inner-city Detroit. She idealistically started her kid in an inner-city school, because she believed the &amp;lsquo;white flight&amp;rsquo; from American cities was a big contributor to cycle of poverty. One day, her child comes home with a gash on her temple because she got in the way of some older kids fighting; a gang thing, the school administration tells her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s #1 Occasional Dictator</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/number-one-dictator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/number-one-dictator/</guid>
      <description>Testing my friends hypothesis, &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t annoy me with talks about politics.&amp;rdquo; (In the tradition of trolling the other while they are lifting weights.)
TEST ONE:
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Gandhi did a creepy chastity experiment with his teenaged nieces.&amp;rdquo;
Friend: &amp;ldquo;I know that.&amp;rdquo;
TEST TWO:
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Modi acted really suspiciously during the Gujarati riots.&amp;rdquo;
Friend: Grunts non-commitadly
TEST THREE:
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;The economic boom in India is due mainly to low oil prices, and the BJP is just taking credit for that without instituting the unpopular sweeping changes the economy really needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The more you know...</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/to-noam-is-to-love-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/to-noam-is-to-love-him/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Oh man, too bad. I would have loved to do a report on Chomsky. After all, to Noam is to love him.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac&amp;rsquo;s Professor: &amp;ldquo;You are more than welcome to write a report on Chomsky [&amp;hellip;] He is certainly an important person to read, these days.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Uh, that&amp;rsquo;s okay, I mostly just wanted to say &amp;lsquo;to Noam is to love him.&#39;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labour Camp</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/labor-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/labor-camp/</guid>
      <description>Isaac&amp;rsquo;s professor: &amp;ldquo;[Taking summer calculus] will probably be the hardest thing you ever do in college. You must study for four to five hours a day. If any of you have full-time jobs, I suggest you take leave from them. This class is like labor camp.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: smiles unwillingly
Isaac&amp;rsquo;s professor: looks at Isaac &amp;ldquo;I see you are laughing. But I am Russian. I know what labor camp is.
Isaac: REALLY smiling now</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations With Missionaries</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/missionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/missionaries/</guid>
      <description>So today I sat down with a couple of missionaries (who often target me I think because I&amp;rsquo;m often alone and sitting outside, reading.) I generally enjoy such conversations, because missionaries are a friendly bunch and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent way more time than your average person thinking about religion.
But during such conversations, there are some cultural mistakes that happen with such regularity, and I feel like we spend most of the conversation correcting those rather than actually getting to the meat of anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/amma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/amma/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Priya&amp;rsquo;s smelly! Priya&amp;rsquo;s proud!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Karthik is so very round!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Priya only primps and preens!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Karthik rarely ever cleans!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Priya&amp;rsquo;s mood is so deflating!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Karthik just won&amp;rsquo;t stop complaining!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Priya hid my cricket bat!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Karthik&amp;rsquo;s head is oddly flat!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Kids,&amp;rdquo; said Amma, commiserating,
&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;You BOTH are very irritating.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/epitaph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/epitaph/</guid>
      <description>Epitaph
If I could swap your life for mine
(If they were ours to trade)
I wonder what you may have done,
And who you might have made.
Perhaps you might have found a way
To ever change the Earth&amp;ndash;
Perhaps you might have had your say,
And shown the world your worth.
Perhaps your name would travel far -
You&amp;rsquo;d hold the world enthralled
The magnitude of who you are</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/valentines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/valentines/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a trick!&amp;rdquo; he shouts, a glint in his eye,
&amp;ldquo;A SCAM made up by those greeting card guys!&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s SLEIGHT OF HAND, dreamed up by dummies,&amp;quot;
The biggest SHAM since &amp;lsquo;healthy&amp;rsquo; fruit gummies!&amp;quot;
The teen by the till&amp;ndash;sullen, sarcastic:
&amp;ldquo;Would you like these chocolates in paper or plastic?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/poems/worlds/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;rsquo;t need a broomstick to fly -
To pass the Quaffle across the sky,
To wrestle with grief whilst walking the woods,
To explore what happens when we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t (but could).
You don&amp;rsquo;t need a rocket to reach the stars
Nor nary a cent to travel afar -
To brave, with Peter and Susan, the snow,
To help deal Durza the final blow.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need a dollar, a pence, or a yen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feline Fiction</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/mr-bunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/mr-bunny/</guid>
      <description>Despite rather badly wanting a dog, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure enough about my lifestyle in the next decade or even five years or so to actually take the leap and buy/adopt one. Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;ve attached myself to two very affectionate local cats that belong to my neighbors, who allow them to walk outside freely most days.
I&amp;rsquo;ve talked briefly to the owners and gotten the cats&#39; names&amp;ndash;Mr. and Mrs. Bunny, and their adopted son Bunny Jr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
