<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Isaac Samuel</title>
    <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Isaac Samuel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 19:04:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Field is not the Job</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/day-to-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/day-to-day/</guid>
      <description>One thing I see people do a lot when choosing a career - not just teenagers, but adults - is conflating a field or a job title with the actual day-to-day of a job.
As an example, my best friend in high school wanted to be a wildlife researcher for most of her life. She had presumably visualized tracking wolves in some remote forest, observing their behaviour, and being in the woods for months at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Ethos</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ethos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ethos/</guid>
      <description>Word vomit on building an &amp;ldquo;ethos&amp;rdquo;/ code of ethics, for the masochistic. (Fair warning: it&amp;rsquo;s very &amp;ldquo;written to a friend at 3AM&amp;rdquo;. Have mercy.) So I always kind of hate how in discussions about fictional characters, or even in-universe, when people judge characters based on what they did in moments of extreme stress. But it&amp;rsquo;s actually a pretty common way of seeing the world. Obviously many believe in things like critical moments where we really get &amp;ldquo;tested&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On &#39;two-hour&#39; friendships</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/two-hour-friendships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/two-hour-friendships/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend, I took a trip to NYC. Before the trip, I killed time by pacing outside the greyhound station. I don&amp;rsquo;t smoke, but when a desi guy came outside and started puffing away, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to bum a cigarette and show off my hindi.
By coincidence, we ended up sitting in adjacent rows of seats on the bus ride, and then happily sat together when the bus got overcrowded and some had to eschew social distancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tightrope</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/tightrope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/tightrope/</guid>
      <description>The thing about trauma is that it reaches inside of you, it changes something fundamental about who you are, and it does so against your will. All you can do after is try and create someone functional using the pieces you have at your disposal.
You must choose a direction, and move - hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s forward, though perhaps your moral compass feels less than trustworthy, lately. You plan and you course-correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horrible History</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ancesteral-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/ancesteral-trauma/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when reading about history, my jaw drops at just how just how cruel the world was. In 1398, just outside of Delhi, the conqueror Amir Taimur killed around 100,000 people. Why? He had captured them, and was worried that they might revolt. This could turn the tides of the next battle, perhaps the war.
So, very logically, he ordered that they all 100,000 people&amp;ndash;lives, families, dreams, and pets&amp;ndash;be slaughtered. (If you, like me, struggle at first glance to emotionally feel anything when you read this, try imagining specific loved ones being killed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formalising Classification Schema</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/classification-schema/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/classification-schema/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m temporarily staying near a state park and have had a lot of opportunity to do my favourite thing&amp;ndash;extended walks in nature where I can go down deep holes I’d typically consider best left to rabbits with pocket watches. Today, my brain apparently decided it was time to formalise and classify different types of nuance (because nothing is more nuanced than a formal classification schema).
I think that one of the most important skills for thinking fairly and accurately is considering nuance: resisting binary dichotomies on complex and important topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On rights</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/rights/</guid>
      <description>In a perfectly totalitarian society, everything that is not approved is criminal. In a perfectly free society, nothing is criminal. In every society that actually exists, there&amp;rsquo;s a middle ground: there are many things we allow people to do even if we don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re a good idea.
For example, in most western countries, it&amp;rsquo;s perfectly legal to eat yourself to morbid obesity, get blackout drunk every night, make flat-earth videos on YouTube, deny the Holocaust, or swear at your boss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Superpowers</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/superpowers/</guid>
      <description>(Just repaired my old laptop, and I&amp;rsquo;m going through my diary entries. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad they were recoverable. Here&amp;rsquo;s one of my (somewhat emotional) retrospectives that I had started a few months ago and finished just now.)
There was some thread online talking about &amp;ldquo;travel superpowers&amp;rdquo;, such as the ability to fall asleep easily in transit, to negotiate with pedlars, or to find cheap accommodation. My answer is something I inherited from my dad - a blithe fearlessness for my physical safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Relations in the Bangalore P.G.: The Screenplay</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cultural-relations-pg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cultural-relations-pg/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved into a P.G. (personal guesthouse) here in Bangalore, a low-commitment and dirt-cheap accommodation that provides food twice daily, perfect for migrant workers and students.
My room is literally a bed in a hallway, so I spend a lot of time interacting with the people who live with me - playing cards, discussing romance &amp;amp; politics, and drinking mysterious liquor of dubious origin.
Thus, I present a 100% accurate screenplay:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gora Problems</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/foriegners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/foriegners/</guid>
      <description>Had an exceptionally good day in Indore, topped by a conversation with a stand-up comedian named Div, who was curious about my perception of India. (I asked him if he had more than fifteen minutes for me to adequately respond to that, and he pointed out that, if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, we were both sitting alone on a Friday night eating &amp;ldquo;fucking poha&amp;rdquo;.) At some point, I mentioned that on the way there, the auto driver had stopped and introduced me to two of his friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isaac&#39;s Checklist For Hard-Balling Autowallas...</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/autowalla/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/autowalla/</guid>
      <description>Isaac&amp;rsquo;s Checklist For Hard-Balling Autowallas That Start Out The Negotiation At 3.5x The Amount You Know It Actually Should Cost To Get To Your Destination:
1.) An amused smile and a &amp;ldquo;Baaaaaaaaapre.&amp;rdquo; The longer and more drawn out, the better - this is a sign of virility in the Maratha culture. Men often sit in a circle and contest each other with how long they can draw out their &amp;ldquo;bapre&amp;quot;s. Having asserted your masculinity, offer the fair price times 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwraveling the Indian Head Bobble</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/head-bobble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/head-bobble/</guid>
      <description>After much time and study, I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve finally cracked the mystery of the Indian Head-Bobble.
All people with association to Indian culture will surely know about the Indian head-bobble. More common in the south than the north, it&amp;rsquo;s a curious side-to-side motion, something like tilting your head around the x-axis.
When I came to India the first time, I first thought it was a somehow deferential way of saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m neither confirming nor denying your assumption&amp;rdquo;, because I saw a teenager use it instead of actually answering when questioned about his activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Service</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/customer-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/customer-service/</guid>
      <description>One of the many idiosyncrasies of India is its customer service.
On one hand, you have the infamous call centers that require 35 digit confirmation numbers (or God help you) and that can&amp;rsquo;t ever seem to use common sense if it requires going off-script. Banks where you literally have to negotiate to open a checking account, or who will send you to three different branches to avoid dealing with you. Thoroughly spiteful building managers who turn off the elevator when guests are over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gunner</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cs-chest-beating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/cs-chest-beating/</guid>
      <description>Today we got back our midterms in my computer science-oriented Probability and Statistics course. The TA told us the highest score was a 48 (out of fifty) and the lowest was in the tens but the average was somewhere in the thirties. The grade will be curved.
Computer science is a discipline full of chest-beating, maybe due to being skewed male and rife with impostor syndrome. One guy in particular is a good example - he complained loudly about covering the material in India during his tenth grade year, he has a tendency to blurt out the answer pre-emptively when the professor is guiding the class on a problem, and he frequently laughs when other students ask a question he feels is obvious (and takes it on himself to explain the answer as condescendingly as humanly possible).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Five Minute Deconstruction of Free Will</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/free-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/free-will/</guid>
      <description>(This way-too-long, way-too-digressive response was written for a discussion about the nature of poverty and whether or not it&amp;rsquo;s a choice. There&amp;rsquo;s a much easier argument to be made that poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t much of a choice in most cases without delving into the philosophical topic of free will, but I&amp;rsquo;m doing this for free, so this is what you get.)
There are a number of approaches you can take to dissolve the concept of free will, and/or the concept of personal responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSI: Applied Statistics</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/csi-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/csi-data-science/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a notion in my mind for a long time&amp;ndash;that the &amp;lsquo;unsexy&amp;rsquo; engineering jobs save more lives than firefighters and first-responders do, by building buildings, cars, and systems (including the equipment firefighters use) to be safe and functional. (So if you want to do something good for the world with you career, being a firefighter works, but keep in mind that people don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate the hard-working engineers whenever a bridge doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall down or when their cell works to call 911 in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Nuance in Racial Discourse</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/thinking-with-naunce-in-race-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/thinking-with-naunce-in-race-discussion/</guid>
      <description>Thought experiment time!
Gina is an upper-middle-class woman who works as a professor in a university in inner-city Detroit. She idealistically started her kid in an inner-city school, because she believed the &amp;lsquo;white flight&amp;rsquo; from American cities was a big contributor to cycle of poverty. One day, her child comes home with a gash on her temple because she got in the way of some older kids fighting; a gang thing, the school administration tells her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s #1 Occasional Dictator</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/number-one-dictator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/number-one-dictator/</guid>
      <description>Testing my friends hypothesis, &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t annoy me with talks about politics.&amp;rdquo; (In the tradition of trolling the other while they are lifting weights.)
TEST ONE:
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Gandhi did a creepy chastity experiment with his teenaged nieces.&amp;rdquo;
Friend: &amp;ldquo;I know that.&amp;rdquo;
TEST TWO:
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Modi acted really suspiciously during the Gujarati riots.&amp;rdquo;
Friend: Grunts non-commitadly
TEST THREE:
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;The economic boom in India is due mainly to low oil prices, and the BJP is just taking credit for that without instituting the unpopular sweeping changes the economy really needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations With Missionaries</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/missionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/thoughts/missionaries/</guid>
      <description>So today I sat down with a couple of missionaries (who often target me I think because I&amp;rsquo;m often alone and sitting outside, reading.) I generally enjoy such conversations, because missionaries are a friendly bunch and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent way more time than your average person thinking about religion.
But during such conversations, there are some cultural mistakes that happen with such regularity, and I feel like we spend most of the conversation correcting those rather than actually getting to the meat of anything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
