<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blurbs on Isaac Samuel</title>
    <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blurbs on Isaac Samuel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 19:04:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/siblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/siblings/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;I know you&amp;rsquo;re joking around, but every time you hit me, I have an intense angry moment in which I have to choose not to hit you back much harder. Stop.&amp;rdquo; $FRIEND: &amp;ldquo;🥺🥺🥺 You&amp;rsquo;d hit me, bro?&amp;rdquo; Isaac: &amp;ldquo;I have far too many siblings to believe in nonviolence.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye Heart Eyes</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/eyes/</guid>
      <description>Wearing masks have really focused my attention on the diversity, expressiveness, and beauty of eyes. I kind of get why artists and poets are so obsessed with them.
(However, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from experience that it&amp;rsquo;s typically an oddball thing to compliment strangers on. 😂 I&amp;rsquo;m typically really free about saying &amp;ldquo;I love your hair!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Nice tattoo, man!&amp;rdquo; to random people. But complimenting people&amp;rsquo;s eyes usually comes across as flirting, or as being on drugs or something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindi troubles</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/spanish/</guid>
      <description>Accidentally asked my hispanic neighbors &amp;ldquo;Spanish samajatha hain?&amp;rdquo; 🤦‍♂️ Apparently for my subconcious, there are two languages: English and Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone-y Bologna</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/time/</guid>
      <description>Me: &amp;ldquo;Where does all my time go? How am I supposed to get anything done? When&amp;rsquo;s the last time I even ate?&amp;rdquo;
Also Me: Spends an hour on the phone with his friend in India
Spends fourty-five minutes on the phone with his friend living three blocks away
Spends an hour and a half on the phone with his best friend&amp;rsquo;s mom
Spends an hour and a half on the phone with his former boss</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boxer Shorts</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/boxers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/boxers/</guid>
      <description>Very random fun fact&amp;ndash;in India, it is customary for men to wear a second pair of underwear underneath their boxers. Which turns them into acceptable loungewear and marginally acceptable attire for a very casual motorcycle ride down to the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/github/</guid>
      <description>Me: Oh, this really long elaborate GitHub issue I wrote two years ago is overcomplicating this. I can do a much simpler thing! Let me just do that.
Me: (spends time doing simple thing)
Me: WAIT AHHHHH
Me: NO THIS DOES NOT WORK WHY DID I NOT TRUST 2016 ME WHO OBVIOUSLY THOUGHT THIS THROUGH DAMN IT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maratha Blues</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/smelly-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/smelly-breath/</guid>
      <description>#1 on the list of things I don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate about Maharastra: How I kind of like the taste of raw onions after living here. This is NOT good for your love lives, guys, just remember that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do-uble Entendre</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/maruti-esteem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/maruti-esteem/</guid>
      <description>I was on an online forum discussing some of India&amp;rsquo;s greatest unsolved mysteries, and someone wrote &amp;ldquo;One of the unsolved mysteries is that someone stole my self esteem and I can&amp;rsquo;t get it back.&amp;rdquo; Until I read someone&amp;rsquo;s response (&amp;ldquo;Bhai Tinder uninstall kar do, self respect wapas aa jayegi&amp;rdquo;), I somehow parsed the poster as saying that his car (a Maruti Esteem) had been stolen.
I should have been tipped off by the idea that someone had stolen that model of car, if nothing else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reunion</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/hugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/hugs/</guid>
      <description>Meeting my best friend Sashank for the first time in a year, and pretty darn ecstatic about it.
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from me.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from Jayesh.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from Meg.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: hugs Sashank &amp;ldquo;Okay, one hug from Meg&amp;rsquo;s mom.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;And my gram gives you the option of either a hug or her love, because she remembers from what I&amp;rsquo;ve described that you&amp;rsquo;re not prone to physical displays of affection and doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to quote &amp;lsquo;freak you out&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bajaranji Bakvaas</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bajarangi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bajarangi/</guid>
      <description>The eighth Harry Potter movie is showing on TV. Harry and Ron are frantically changing out of wet clothes after jumping into a lake
$Host_Sister: &amp;ldquo;Why don&amp;rsquo;t they just change their clothes using magic?&amp;rdquo;
Isaac (aggrieved): &amp;ldquo;If Hanuman could grow so big he could fly a mountain from the Himalayas, why didn&amp;rsquo;t he just carry the army into Lanka instead of making everyone build a land bridge?&amp;rdquo;
Cue: Twenty-minute family argument, /w some yelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Exchange</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bribing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/bribing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Arre, you bribed the ticket walla?!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;No I didn&amp;rsquo;t! I tipped him&amp;hellip; and he gave me super special service in return. I mean, nobody was using these seats [in first class] and apparently they have the discretion to upgrade people.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;And you just paid him to use his discretion. That is called bribing.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Well, in America we call it tipping.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysterious Ways</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/brains-mysterious-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/brains-mysterious-ways/</guid>
      <description>Brains work in, uh, mysterious ways. Today, I observed the weirdest instance of mine getting its &amp;ldquo;wires crossed&amp;rdquo;.
In lieu of change, a salesclerk gave me a couple pieces of expresso candy. My intention afterwards was to eat a piece of candy and simultaneously start a work task.
I sat down and popped the candy in my mouth, all according to plan. But suddenly, I felt a surge of alarm, convinced for a split-second that I had somehow eaten the task I was intending to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karthick Bhee Hain</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/dostana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/dostana/</guid>
      <description>Adventures working as a server in an Indian restaurant
Isaac (to customer): &amp;ldquo;Aapka naam kyaa hain [to call when your order is ready]?&amp;rdquo;
Customer: &amp;ldquo;Karthick hoon.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Oh, is it? Ek second, meh phone call lena zarurat hoon.&amp;rdquo; Mimes picking up the phone &amp;ldquo;Wow, call aap ke lie!&amp;rdquo;
Customer: &amp;ldquo;Kyaa?&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Voh bol ki uska naam Karthick bhee hain. I guess&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s Karthick calling Karthick.&amp;rdquo;
Customer &amp;amp; friend: look confused and then laugh simutanously</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meh Americano Samajatha Hoon</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/coffee-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/coffee-india/</guid>
      <description>Am at the airport in Bangalore. On less than an hour sleep, I did what had to be the most stereotypically American-tourist thing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done (and I feel no shame).
Worker: &amp;ldquo;Sir, what kind [of coffee] would you like?&amp;rdquo;
Me: &amp;ldquo;Uhhhh, what are the options?&amp;rdquo;
Worker: &amp;ldquo;Sir, cappachino, americano, latte&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Do you have just like, regular coffee?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pani Hai</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/rum-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/rum-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>On my daily commute home, I was carrying some rum to share for a birthday party in our P.G. After my bag went through the scanner at the metro station and I retrieved it, the female guard ran after me and indicated I needed to talk to the analyst about something he saw on the scanner.
Analyst: &amp;ldquo;Water bottle?&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Nei nei. Um&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Unzips bag to show contents)
Analyst (smiling as he examines the rum bottle): &amp;ldquo;Water bottle hai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux Maturity</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/faux-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/faux-maturity/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms of faux maturity:
 Avoiding things you&amp;rsquo;d find fun because they are not what an &amp;ldquo;adult&amp;rdquo; does. (E.g. Dyeing your hair purple, playing video games.) Doing things you hate because they ARE what an &amp;ldquo;adult&amp;rdquo; does. (Buying a house, tending to a lawn, smoking, drinking coffee or alcohol.) Shaming or thinking less of people for doing harmless but weird or non-age-typical things. (Scoffing at someone for watching cartoons or putting M&amp;amp;Ms on their pizza.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthropological Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/crosscultural-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/crosscultural-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>Isaac&amp;rsquo;s mandatory mental checklist whilst hanging out with his (majority desi / south asian) friends:
 Make an extremely convoluted conclusion about desi culture. What observations cause you to draw this conclusion? What assumptions are supporting the way you notice and interpret those actions? In what scenarios could those assumptions possibly be legitimate or illegitimate, and is that even a clearly defined boundary? Am I overthinking this? I’m overthinking this. This is not how a normal person hangs out with their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s called shoestring travelling, and there&#39;s a SUBREDDIT, thank you</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/where-are-your-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/where-are-your-parents/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s completely possible to travel in India for less than $200 a month. You just have to be willing to give up all pretense of safety and comfort. Mostly, just be gregarious with people you meet in general and even on the street - they&amp;rsquo;ll invite you to stay with them, and your travels will totally be enriched.&amp;rdquo;
Boss (exasperated, horrified): &amp;ldquo;Isaac, where were your parents?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakari Bakvaas</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/goats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/goats/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s just replace every word in every sentence with the word &amp;lsquo;goat&amp;rsquo;. Ready? Goat.&amp;rdquo;
$FRIEND_1: &amp;ldquo;Goat goat goat goat.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Goat goat goat. Goat goat goat goat goat goat?&amp;rdquo;
$FRIEND_1: &amp;ldquo;Goat. Goat?&amp;rdquo;
$FRIEND_2: &amp;ldquo;Haha, alright guys.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Goat goat?! Goat goat, goat goat goat goat goat goat! GOAT!&amp;rdquo; shakes Sashank &amp;ldquo;GOOOOAAAAAT!&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramayario</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/ramario/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/ramario/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely the last thing on my priority list right now, but it occurred to me that it would be a lot of fun to make a Ramayana version of the Mario games where Mario is Rama, Sita is Peach, Donkey Kong is Hanuman, and Bowser is Ravana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monkey Business</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/monkey-buisiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/monkey-buisiness/</guid>
      <description>(While hiking in a state park with a friend recently from Mumbai)
Friend: &amp;ldquo;Isaac, you should ask one of us to watch of your bag while you&amp;rsquo;re climbing.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;I feel pretty safe. Are you worried about something in particular?&amp;rdquo;
Friend: &amp;ldquo;Monkeys could get into it and mess with your stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen that happen so many times.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Monkeys are less of a problem in the US.&amp;rdquo;
Friend (skeptically): &amp;ldquo;Okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The more you know...</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/to-noam-is-to-love-him/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/to-noam-is-to-love-him/</guid>
      <description>Isaac: &amp;ldquo;Oh man, too bad. I would have loved to do a report on Chomsky. After all, to Noam is to love him.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac&amp;rsquo;s Professor: &amp;ldquo;You are more than welcome to write a report on Chomsky [&amp;hellip;] He is certainly an important person to read, these days.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Uh, that&amp;rsquo;s okay, I mostly just wanted to say &amp;lsquo;to Noam is to love him.&#39;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labour Camp</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/labor-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 19:04:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/labor-camp/</guid>
      <description>Isaac&amp;rsquo;s professor: &amp;ldquo;[Taking summer calculus] will probably be the hardest thing you ever do in college. You must study for four to five hours a day. If any of you have full-time jobs, I suggest you take leave from them. This class is like labor camp.&amp;rdquo;
Isaac: smiles unwillingly
Isaac&amp;rsquo;s professor: looks at Isaac &amp;ldquo;I see you are laughing. But I am Russian. I know what labor camp is.
Isaac: REALLY smiling now</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feline Fiction</title>
      <link>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/mr-bunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacsamuel.github.io/blog/blurbs/mr-bunny/</guid>
      <description>Despite rather badly wanting a dog, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure enough about my lifestyle in the next decade or even five years or so to actually take the leap and buy/adopt one. Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;ve attached myself to two very affectionate local cats that belong to my neighbors, who allow them to walk outside freely most days.
I&amp;rsquo;ve talked briefly to the owners and gotten the cats&#39; names&amp;ndash;Mr. and Mrs. Bunny, and their adopted son Bunny Jr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
